

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Details

Laubacher StraBe 2,
Berlin, 14197
Germany
03039771601
kinjalmore2015@gmail.com

NATIONALITY

Indian

DATE / PLACE OF BIRTH

10/31/1992

india

Links

LinkedIn

Skills

Git

JavaScript
NodeJS
ReactJS
Laravel Framework
PHP
mysql
AWS
Docker
MongoDB
MySQL
PostgreSQL

Profile

Over 7 years of extensive experience in web-based applications. Worked mainly with application software analysis, design, development, and testing of web (all the phases of SDLC and quality assurance/testing). Skilled in NodeJS, ExpressJS-, TypeScript, Micro-Services, Laravel, PHP, Lumen, ReactJS, MongoDB, HTML, jQuery, and Bootstrap. To seek a challenging position in a company to a motivating and vibrant work environment, on the basis of my knowledge, fast learning, and creative skills. Able to work independently with little or no supervision and a dedicated team player. I am holding Germany Visa and ready to join immediately.

Employment History

Full Stack Developer, DevDigital, Vadodara, India

MARCH 2021 - PRESENT

- Expertise in modern web architecture using various advanced JavaScript frameworks and libraries like NodeJS, ReactJS/Redux, bootstrap, material UI, ES7, ES6, ES5, and Typescript features for handling asynchronous data requests.
- Expertise in MERN (MongoDB, ExpressJS, ReactJS, and NodeJS) stack applications.
- Worked on AWS large project using AWS Cognito, Lambda, API gateway, node back-end, MySQL, store procedure React/Redux front-end.
- Worked on AWS RDS database and EC2 instance integration
- Worked on complex 3-tier architecture and complex system form.
- Expertise using React Component, Reducers, and Actions to implement MVC and Redux architecture and having experience with Middleware.
- Working as a Technical Lead involves client handling, and joining the scrum calls and client meetings. Involved in creating different types of documents on an organizational level
- NodeJS Deploy on AWS CDK by using the Docker container
- Integrated Stripe and RazorPay payment gateway
- Store and fetch API request responses on the AWS server
- Functionality changes and implementing new features
- Webhook and RESTAPI integration.

Software Developer, Corigami Technologies pvt ltd, Vadodara

JANUARY 2019 - MARCH 2021

- RESTful API design and development using NodeJS, ExpressJS, PHP, Laravel and Lumen.
- Extensively used Promises, async, await and event emitter in NodeJS to avoid callbacks and more readable code.
- Build great online seamless user experience using modern frameworks and libraries.
- Good understanding of Document Object Model (DOM), DOM Funtion,
 ReactJS Componant, Redux
- manage different API responses in a single one by using micro-services.
- Responsible for writing server-side web application logic, developing back-end
 components, connecting the application with the other (often third-party) web
 services, and supporting the front-end developers by integrating their work
 with the application.
- Worked on different API integration and worked on a complex pricing module
- Sound Understanding and good experience with Object Oriented Concepts,
 Object Oriented JavaScript, Object Oriented Design and Implementation

 Architected and lead the transition from monolith to a cloud-based microservice architecture on AWS

Software Developer, www.purchasekaro.com, Vadodara

JULY 2017 - DECEMBER 2018

- worked on making micro-services and third party API integration like hotel booking api, bus booking api,flight booking api,payment gateway api, domestic money transfer api.
- experience with SQL schema design, SOLID principles, REST API design .

•

- Strong grip on api creation and api integration.
- Expertise in developing and updating web pages quickly using JavaScript, jQuery, and ReactJs
- worked on B2B, B2C portals
- good working experience with LAMP Linux, Apache, MySQL, PHP and WAMPP Window, Apache, MySQL, PHP environment.

Web Developer, Myrestica Technologies PVT LTD, Vadodara

JULY 2015 - JUNE 2017

- Developing and making code more modular by using the Model View Control (MVC)
- Database designing for regular and e-commerce portals
- Developed user interface using PHP, Codeigniter, Laravel, and JavaScript.
- Strong grip on object-oriented programming
- Developed AJAX functionalities using JQUERY.
- MYSQL ERD database designing.
- Changes in woo-commerce plugin.
- Proficiant in object oriented programming OOPS concepts of PHP, ability to quickly learn and apply new technologies.

Education

Bachelor's in Information Technology, University of Gujrat, Vadodara

JULY 2010 - JUNE 2014

Backend Technology

- Laravel, Lumen, Codelgniter, PHP.
- NodeJS, ReactJs, ExpressJS, AWS Services.

Frontend Technology

- Javascript, ES6, ES7
- ReactJs, VueJS, NodeJs.
- AJAX, BootStrap, Material UI, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Jquery.

Database:

- MYSQL, SQL. PostgreSQL
- Mongo DB, PouchDB, CouchDB.

Other Tool

 AWS services (Lambda, S3 bucket, Cloud Watch, Users, CDK, SDK, SAM CLI, Cloud Formation, Cloud Front, RDS, API gateway, Secret Manager, EC2 instance, Cognito User).

- Git, Jira, bitbucket.Worked on AWS project created API using AWS lambda and API gateway
- Postman, Docker, and ITPoker for time estimation

About Me

I am a very hard-working person. I keenly believe in updating my skills constantly. I am a nature-loving person and I love visiting beautiful places. I enjoy listening to soft music and reading in my free time.